♪
♪ Take a step
to the left and right ♪
♪ The left and right ♪
♪ Throw your hands
strap in the sky♪
♪ like an amusement ride ♪
♪ Next your head,
you put it at your feet ♪
♪ And stick your arm
to the side ♪
♪ And shake your hand
like it's gone to sleep ♪
♪ And that's the blackjack way,
come on! ♪
♪ Take a step
to the left and right ♪
♪ The left and right ♪
♪ Throw your hands
straight up in the sky ♪
♪ Like an amusement ride ♪
♪ Next your head,
put it at your feet ♪
♪ And stick your arm
to the side ♪
♪ Shake your hand
like it's gone to sleep ♪
♪ And that's the blackjack way ♪
♪ Take a step
to the left and right ♪
♪ The left and right ♪
♪ Throw your hands
straight up in the sky ♪
♪ Like an amusement ride ♪
♪ Next your head,
you put it at your feet ♪
♪ And stick your arm
to the side ♪
♪ And shake your hand
like it's gone to sleep ♪
♪ And that's
the blackjack way. ♪
청소부가 한 시간 쯤 전에 발견했어요
FLACK: Cleaning crew found
him about an hour ago.
교장은 오고 있는 중이고요
Principal's on his way in now.
토요일에 도서관에서 뭐하고 있던 거지?
What was he doing
here on a Saturday?
아침에 SAT 시험이 있었거든요
The SATs were this morning.
가장 좋은 추측은, 피해자는
어젯밤 공부를 하고 있었는데
Best guess, he was
studying late last night,
관리자가 아무도 없는 줄
알고 문을 잠근거겠죠
someone locked up without
knowing he was here.
자식이 귀가하지 않았는데
부모는 신고도 안 한건가?
Kid doesn't come home
and his parents don't report it?
가정사라는건 모를 일이니까요
Who knows what
his home life was like?
치명적이고 깊은 외상이군
Blunt and sharp force trauma.
찾으시는 흉기가
여기 있는 것 같은데요?
Here's your murder
weapon right here.
무슨일이 있었든지간에 확실한건
Whatever happened,
it's safe to say
범인은 계획적으로 움직이지는 않았네요
our perp didn't have
much of a plan.
그리고 피해자는 완전히 무너진거지
And our vic's was snuffed out.
자막제작 - 베카★ 수정/배포 자유
sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com
♪ Out here in the fields
♪ I fight for my meals
♪ I get my back into my living
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
(camera shutter clicks)
♪
포스트지도 데일리 뉴스도 안 됩니다
No to the Post,
no to the Daily News.
저희도 언급할게 있어야
언급이란 걸 하지 않겠습니까
I'll have a comment when there's
something to comment on.
피해자의 가방에서 나온건가?
Those in the vic's backpack?
네, 덱스트로암페타민이에요
* 각성제나 식욕 억제제로 사용
Yeah. Dextroamphetamines.
피해자가 ADHD를 앓고 있었을지 모르죠
Vic might have
suffered from ADHD.
그리고 신원을 알아냈는데
Did have an I.D., though.
가방 안에 피해자의 신분증이 있었어요
Wallet was in the vic's
backpack.
루크 스티븐슨,
94년 12월 8일생이네요
Uh, Luke Stevenson,
DOB: 8/12/94.
루크 스티븐슨?
Luke Stevenson?
주소가 어떻게 되지?
What's the address?
브루클린 킹스 로우 1013번지요
1013 Kings Row, Brooklyn.
♪
사건현장에서 어젯밤
8시 쯤에 연락이 왔네
MAN: Got called to a scene
around 8:00 last night.
집에 돌아 왔을 땐
루크 방문이 닫혀있었고
When I got home,
his door was closed.
그 애가 이미 잠들었다고 생각했지
I assumed he was asleep.
오늘 아침에 SAT 시험이
있는 줄 알았으니까
I knew he had
the SAT this morning.
정말 유감이네, 프랭크
I'm so sorry, Frank.
내가 자네 전부인에게 전화하지
I can call your ex-wife.
아니, 내가 하겠네
No, I'll tell her.
나한테서 듣는게 더 나을거야
She should hear it from me.
정말 이해할 수가 없어
(voice breaking):
I don't understand.
루크는 정말 착한 아이였어, 알지?
He was such a good kid,
you know?
자네도 만나 봤잖나
You met him.
잘못같은 건 한적이 없었어
He never did anything wrong.
단 한개도 말이야
Not a damn thing.
우리 쪽엔 아직 정보가
많이 없어, 프랭크
We don't know much
right now, Frank.
뭐라도 알려줄 내용 없나?
Is there anything
you can tell me?
잘 모르겠어
I don't know.
(exhales)
일주일 전에, 루크의 친구인
네이트, 네이크 폴슨이
A week ago, his friend Nate,
Nate Paulson,
약물과 알콜을 혼합
남용해서 사망했네
he OD'd mixing prescription
meds with alcohol.
루크에게는 꽤 힘든 일이었어
It was rough on Luke.
하지만 루크는 괜찮아보였네
But he seemed okay.
그거에 대해서 이야기도 나누었는걸
We talked about it.
어떤 종류의 약물이었나?
What kind of meds?
나도 모르겠어
I don't know.
혹시 루크가 ADHD를 앓았나?
Did Luke have ADHD?
집중력 장애말인가?
Attention deficit?
아니
No.
왜 그런걸 묻는건데?
Why are you asking me?
루크의 가방에서 약들을 발견했거든
We found a bag of pills
in his backpack.
덱스트로암페타민이었지
Dextroamphetamines.
주로 이용되는 게..
They're used to treat...
나도 어디 쓰이는지는 알아
I know what they're used for.
루크는 ADHD를 앓지 않았어
Luke didn't have ADHD.
혹시 친구의 죽음이
자네의 생각보다 더 루크에게
Is it possible he could have
taken his friend's death
영향을 준 건 아니었을까?
harder than you think?
그 일로 정신적 스트레스를 받아서..
Maybe he was having
trouble dealing with...
그건 루크게 아니네
They weren't his.
- 프랭크
- 루크 약이 아니야
- Frank.
- They weren't his.
대체.. 대체 나한테
무슨 말을 하려는건가?
What... what are you
telling me?
내 아들이 취하려고 약을 했다고?
That he was using them
to get high?
내 말은 그게 아니네
That's not what I'm saying.
그런 뭔가?
He was what?
지금 내 아들이
무슨 마약 중독자고
That he was, uh,
some drug addict,
난 그걸 알지도 못했다고?
and I didn't even know about it?
프랭크, 내 말을 좀 듣게
Frank, just listen to me.
내가 하려는 말은 그게 아니야
That's not what I'm saying.
나도 알 수가 없네
I don't know that.
아이들은 여러가지
이유로 약을 먹지 않나
Kids use this stuff for
all kinds of reasons.
더 오래 공부하거나
To study longer.
시험에 조금 더 집중하기 위해
Focus better on their exams.
루크는 SAT에다가
대학 원서까지 써야했잖나
With the SAT's coming up
and college applications,
그것 때문에 스트레스를
받았을 수 있..
he could have just
been stressed, and...
아니, 절대 아니야
No. No way.
내 아들은 아니야
Not my boy.
(cell phone vibrates)
자기야, 나야
DANNY:
Hey, it's me.
아무래도 아직 잠들어 있는 것 같네
I figured you might
still be sleeping.
밤샌 비행 때문에 많이 피곤하지?
Red-eye probably
knocked you out, huh?
자기가 괜찮은지 자기 목소리 듣고
I just wanted
to hear your voice
얼굴을 좀 보고 싶어서 전화했어
and see if you're
doing all right.
지금 머릿속이 많이 복잡한 거 알아
You don't want
to get into it, I know.
난 그저.. 나도 내가 무슨
생각을 하는지 모르겠네
I just thought...
I don't know what I thought.
그저 자기가 괜찮은지
알고 싶을 뿐이야
I just want to know
that you're okay.
이야기하고 싶으면 언제든지 전화해줘
So call me back if you feel
like talking, please.
아버님께 안부 전해드리고
Say hey to your dad for me.
알겠지? 사랑해
All right? I love you.
얘야, 준비 다 됐지?
Hey. You ready?
아침도 안 먹은걸요
I haven't even
eaten yet.
트럭에서 먹으면 되잖니?
Eat in the truck.
서두르자, 우리 잠꾸러기
Come on, sleepyhead.
어서 가야지
Let's go.
알겠어요, 알겠어, 알겠다고요
Okay, okay, okay.
프랭크가 맡은 사건에
증언을 하러 여러번 갔었네
I testified for Frank
on numerous homicides.
언제나 아들의 이야기를 했지
He would always
talk about him.
이 애가 하는 모든걸 자랑스러워 했어
Always so proud
of how he was doing.
프랭크는 제가 처음 맡은 사건을
He tried my first case
담당했었죠
on the job.
루크는 겨우 한 살이었고요
Luke was only a year old.
좋네
Okay.
특별히 보고할게 없다는게 유감스럽군
Uh, nothing particularly
unique to report, I'm afraid.
사인은 예상대로네
COD is as expected.
머리에 가해진 둔기에 의한 외상이지
Blunt and sharp force
trauma to the head.
여러번의 가격
Multiple blows,
이걸 보면 어떤 종류의
분노가 있었던 것 같네
which suggests some
kind of rage, perhaps.
머그잔 조각을 찾았는데
I extracted a shard of the mug
상처에 다른 작은 조각들과
함께 박혀 있었네
that lodged in the wound tract,
among other, smaller pieces.
약물 검사는 깨끗했네
Toxicology was
completely clean.
- 그러니 이 경우에 사인은..
- 잠시만요
- Uh, the same could not be said...
- Hang on.
약물이 깨끗했다고요?
Tox showed nothing?
어떤 외부 물질도 감지 되지 않았네
No foreign
substances detected.
하지만 자네가 요구한대로
네이트 폴슨의 검시결과는
But I pulled the autopsy
report for Nate Paulson,
미리 뽑아놨지
like you asked.
당시 체내에 400밀리그램이 넘는
He had in excess
of 400 milligrams
덱스트로암페타민이 검출되었다네
of dextroamphetamine
in his system.
거기에 혈중 알콜 농도가 0.24였고
Plus a blood alcohol level
of .24.
덱스트로암페타민은 체내에
얼마 동안이나 남아있죠?
How long does dextroamphetamine
stay in the system?
반감기를 묻는거라면 10시간인데
Uh, the half-life
is about, uh, ten hours,
섭취한 양과 식단, 그리고
신진 대사도 고려해야 하네
so depending on the amount
taken and diet and metabolism,
그러니 약을 한 번 섭취하고 나면
it would still be
present anywhere
3-4일이 지나도 남아 있을 수 있지
from three to four days
after ingestion.
뭔가 맞지 않아요
Something's not right.
루크의 가방에 암페타민이 있었죠
Luke had dextro in his backpack.
SAT를 대비한다고 치면
일주일은 밤을 샜을텐데
He was probably up all week,
studying for the SAT's.
그럼 죽을 당시에도
약을 하고 있었어야해요
He was cramming for it
when he was killed.
그렇다면 분명 체내에서
암페타민이 검출되었어야 하고요
That's exactly when he would
have the stuff in his system,
루크가 이 약을
공부용으로 사용한거라면
so... if he was using the
pills as a study drug,
왜 체내에서 성분이
검출되지 않는거죠?
why aren't they
in his system?
이런말을 하고 싶지는 않네만,
만약 소유하고 있는데
I hate to say it, but if he
was in possession of it
사용하지는 않았다면..
but not using it...
판매하고 있던거겠군요
He was selling it.
그렇다면 약은 누구로부터 얻은걸까요?
But where was he
getting it from?
혹스, 자네가 루크의 가방에서
찾은 암페타민을 넣은
Hawkes, you have the plastic
bag of dextro recovered
비닐 봉지 가지고 있나?
from Luke's backpack?
네, 바로 여기있어요 반장님
Yeah, it's right here, Mac.
그럼 하던거 멈추고
Drop what you're doing.
- 거기서 지문 검사 먼저 하게
- 알겠습니다
- I need you to print the bag.
- You got it.
♪
빌리 월튼
TAYLOR:
Billy Wharton?
피해자의 학교에 다니는군
He goes to our vic's school.
프랭크가 맞았어
Frank was right.
약은 루크의 것이 아니었어
The drugs weren't Luke's.
우!
Oof.
이런, 꼬마야
Damn, kid.
좀 씻고 살자, 우리
Do a wash, my man.
택시 기사 냄새도
이것보다는 낫겠네
Cab drivers smell
better than this.
만족하세요?
Satisfied?
제 사물함 전부를 뒤지셨잖아요
You've gone through
both my lockers.
그럼.. 그럼 이제 뭘 찾는지
좀 말씀해 주실래요?
Can... can you just tell me
what you're looking for?
우리가 뭘 찾는지는
이미 알고 있을 것 같은데?
I think you know
what we're looking for.
사실은 전혀요,
그러니 저한테 말 좀 해주실래요?
Actually, I don't,
so can you please just tell me?
왜냐면 이 상황이 좀 무섭거든요
Because I'm
a little scared here.
분명히, 뭔가 루크와
연관 된 일이겠고요
Obviously, this has
something to do with Luke.
하버드는 너같은 똑똑한
아이를 받게 되서 행운이겠어
Harvard would be lucky to
have someone as smart as you.
이거에 대해서 할 이야기 없니?
What can you tell us
about these?
어.. 어디서..
어디서 그걸 찾으신 거에요?
Wh-Where did...
where did you find those?
루크의 가방에서
Luke's backpack.
분명히 연관되어 있을 줄 알았어
I thought it might
have been him.
루크가 그걸 훔쳤어요
He-he stole those.
제 사물함에서요
From my locker.
너도 이걸 판거야?
You dealing, too?
루크는 네걸 훔치고?
He steal your stash?
그러다가 다툼이 생기고
You guys get into an argument?
일이 지나치게 된 건가?
Things get out of hand?
암페타민 좀 했다고 이걸
팔았다고 하시는거에요?
I take dextro
and you jump to me dealing?
전 마약 딜러같은게 아니에요
I'm not a drug dealer, sir.
전 이거에 대한 처방전도 있다고요
I-I have
a prescription for those.
그런데 이걸 왜 비닐봉지에 넣은거지?
Why were they in a plastic bag?
제가 ADHD를 가지고 있다고
홍보할 필요는 없으니까요
I'm not exactly looking
to advertise that I have ADHD.
전.. 전 그저 학교를
올 때 약통을 갖고
I-I don't... I don't need to be
carrying a prescription bottle
오고 싶지 않았어요
around school.
너와 루크 사이에 큰 다툼이
있었다는 건 이미 알고 있단다
We know there's bad blood
between you and Luke.
바로 어제 아침에 일이었지
As recently
as yesterday morning.
루크, 내가 봤어
Luke, I saw you.
네가 내 답을 배끼는 걸 말야
You were copying
off my exam.
알겠지만 이게 걸리면,
나도 큰일난다고
Now, you know, if you get
caught, it's my ass, too.
이봐, 내 말 들어
Hey, listen to me.
그러니까 만약 우리
답이 너무 비슷하면..
I mean, if our answers
are too similar...
내 앞에서 당장 비키라고
Get the hell out
of my face, man.
도대체 넌 뭐가 문젠데?
What's wrong with you?
이봐, 이봐! 떨어지렴!
Hey, hey, break it up.
그만하라고!
That's enough!
이제 그만하라고 말하잖니!
That's enough, I said!
둘 중 하나는 이게 무슨
일인지 말해야 할거다
One of you better tell me
what this is about.
그러다 코너스 선생님이 나타난거죠
And when Mr. Connors broke it up.
물론 거기서 고자질할 수 있었지만,
그러지 않았어요
I mean, I could have ratted on
him right there, but I didn't.
계속 입을 다물었죠
I kept my mouth shut.
루크를 친구라고 생각해서요
I considered Luke a friend.
이제 가도 되나요?
Can I go?
그러니까.. 이미 연습에 늦었거든요
I mean, I'm already
late for practice.
다 맞아 떨어지네요
Kid's pretty smooth.
모든 상황에 답을 가지고 있고요
He's got an answer
for everything.
너무 맞지
Too smooth.
저 아이의 부모님에게
처방전을 확인하고
See if his parents
can confirm the prescriptions
전화기록에 제출명령을 받아내게
and subpoena his
phone records.
그리고 애덤에게 갖다 줘
Get them to Adam.
만약 다 깨끗하다면,
프랭크에게 우리가 찾은
If he's clean, I want
to be able to tell Frank
모든 것을 이야기해주어야 할거야
that we looked at everything.
루스터 테일이구나, 그렇지?
Rooster tail, huh?
어릴 때처럼 말이죠
Worked when I was a kid.
아무래도 송어는
잡힐 것 같지가 않네요
I'm guessing the trout
haven't wised up any.
우리가 왜 이러고 있는지
아빠가 또 설득해도 되겠니?
Any chance I can convince you
to keep what you catch?
알겠지만 마늘과 함께 팬에 구워낸..
You know, pan-seared
with a little garlic...
아니요
No.
(chuckles)
여기서 뭐하고 있는거니, 린지?
What are you doing here, Linds?
무슨 말씀이세요?
What do you mean?
- 아빠가 데리고 나오셨잖아요
- 아니, 집 말이다
- You brought me out here.
- No, home.
집에서 뭘 하고 있는 거니?
What are you doing home?
제가 집에 오지
말았어야 한다는 거세요?
What, you think I
shouldn't have come?
그게 아니잖니
Come on.
아빠야 너 보는게 좋지,
너도 알고 있잖니
I love seeing you.
You know that.
그저 네가 여기서 무엇을
달성하고 싶은지
Just wondering what you
think you can accomplish
궁금해서 그런단다
by being here.
무슨 말씀이세요, 달성이라니?
What do you mean, accomplish?
그 남자에게서 느끼는 감정말이다
The way you feel about him.
네가 마음 속에 가지고 있는 그것들
The things you got
going on inside of you.
넌 아마 내일도 오늘과
다름 없는 기분일 거란다
You're still going to feel
those same things tomorrow.
아마도요
Maybe.
그래서 절 데리고 나오신거에요?
Is that why you
brought me out here?
아빠는 널 모든 것에서 보호하고 싶거든
I just want to protect you, is all.
어느 아빠가 그러하듯이 말이다
That's all any father wants.
(Robert exhales)
이런, 언제나 그러지
Boy, I tried,
하지만 너도 모든 것으로부터
아이를 보호할 수는 없단다
but you can't protect your
daughter from everything.
결국에는 그런 날이 오게 되거든,
무릎이 까진 너를
Eventually, the day comes
when you have to pick her up
하늘 위로 들어서 안아주며
off the ground
after she skins her knee
모두 다 괜찮아 질거라고 말하는거지
and tell her everything's
going to be all right.
아니면 어떤 녀석때문에 상처 받은
Or wipe away the tears
딸의 눈물을 닦아주는 일도 있지
after some boy
breaks her heart.
엄마의 사망 소식을
어떻게 전하나 고민하는 것도
Find the words to tell her
her mother's gone.
하지만 그게 인생이란다
But that's life.
너한테 모든 걸 가르쳐주지 못했지,
넌 시도 조차도 못하게 했고
I couldn't teach you everything,
and you wouldn't even let me.
넌 스스로의 생각을
가지고 있었으니까, 하지만..
You have your own way
of doing things, but...
난 더 이상 그런 꼬마가 아닌걸요, 아빠
I'm not that little girl
anymore, Dad.
벌써 많은 시간이 흘렀잖아요
I haven't been for a long time.
저도 아빠가 절
자랑스러워하는걸 알아요
And I know you're
proud of me,
하지만 전 아빠가
원하시지 않은 일들을 했고
but I know that you wish
I didn't do what I do.
그런걸 보기도 했어요
Or see the things I see.
그런 순수함은 이미 오래전에 사라졌어요
That innocence was gone
a long time ago.
그리고 전 제가 한
선택들을 후회하지 않아요
And I don't regret
the choices that I've made,
제가 보았던 것들을 후회하지 않고요
and I don't regret seeing
the things I've seen.
넌 정말 멋진 숙녀란다, 린지
You're an impressive
young woman, Lindsay.
하지만 너무나 빨리 커 버렸지
But you grew up so fast.
내가 하고 싶은 말은,
너무 많은 걸 본 게 아니니?
What I'm trying to say is,
haven't you seen enough?
오, 내가 맞춰볼까?
Oh, let me guess.
삶은 우리의
호흡으로 측정되지 않지만
"Life is not measured
by the breaths we take
순간은 우리의
호흡을 앗아갈 수 있다
but by the moments
that take our breath away."
비슷했어요, 하지만 정답은
That's close.
It's actually,
어디에 내 파티, 파-파티,
파티, 파-파티 친구들이 있지?
"Where my party, p-party,
party, p-party people at?"
넬리죠
* 미국의 유명 랩퍼
It's Nelly.
그게 내 두번째 추측이었어
That would have been
my second guess.
- 여자가 관련있다고?
- 혹스가 회중시계에서
- What's up with her?
- Blonde hair Hawkes recovered
금발 머리카락을 찾았어요
from the pocket watch.
DNA 결과가 일치하는 건 없었죠
I ran it for DNA, but no hit.
하지만 이건 심하게 손상됐죠
However, it's, uh,
badly damaged.
심각하게 건조한데다 피질이 갈라지고
It's severely dry,
had a split cortex,
약간의 녹색기까지 있었어요
and also has a
slight green tinge.
그래서 넌 이게
수영선수 거라고 생각하는거고?
So, you're thinking it
belonged to a swimmer.
바로 그거에요
Exactly.
염소와 구리, 철 그리고
망간 성분이 나왔어요
Found traces of chlorine,
copper, iron and manganese,
모두 수영장 안에서
발견되는 것들이죠
all of which are found
in a swimming pool.
길이와 색을 봤을 때
일치하는 건 멜라니 로저스네
The length and color are
consistent with Melanie Rogers.
수영 팀에는 다른 다섯명의
여자애들도 있긴 했지만
Along with five other
girls on the swim team,
네이트 폴슨과 데이트한 건
단 한 사람뿐이죠
but only one of them
was dating Nate Paulson.
암페타민과 알콜로 사망한 아이 말이지
The kid who OD'd
on dextro and alcohol.
붐
Boom.
마지막 50미터가 인상적이더구나
Impressive last 50 meters.
감사해요
Thanks.
난 연구소의 조 댄빌이고,
이 쪽은 플랙 형사란다
I'm Jo Danville, crime lab.
This is Detective Flack.
- 남자친구 소식은 정말 유감이란다
- 네
- Sorry to hear about your
boyfriend, Nate. - Yeah.
그리고 이젠 루크에게도 일이 생겼지
And now, with what's
happened to Luke,
꽤나 힘든 상황이었을 것 같구나
I bet it's been pretty rough.
시간이 지나서 좀 나아졌어요
I've had better weeks.
다행스럽게도, 수영을 하는
동안에는 생각하지 않을 수 있거든요
Luckily, I have this
to keep my mind off of it.
그럼 아주 조금만
그 일에 대해서 생각을
Well, I'm going to need
your mind to think about it
해 줄 수 있겠니?
just for a few more moments.
미안하구나
Sorry.
우리는 네이트의 체내에서
400밀리그램에 엠페타민을 찾았단다
We found over 400 milligrams
of dextro in Nate's system
그 아이가 떠난 후에 말이지
after he passed away.
그 앤 떠난게 아니에요
He didn't pass away.
과용으로.. 죽은거죠
He OD'd.
복용 사실을 알고 있었니?
Did you know he was taking it?
네이트는 중독되어 있었어요
He was addicted to it.
어느 때는 기뻤다가 또
어느 순간에는 우울했죠
One minute he was happy,
the next depressed.
우리는 거의 모든 것 때문에 싸웠고요
We fought about
practically everything.
그 앤 처음 만났을 때와는
He wasn't the same person
전혀 다른 사람이 되어 있었어요
as when we first
started dating.
어디서 약을 구하는지는 알고 있니?
Do you know
where he was getting it?
루크에게서부터 약을
얻은거지, 그렇지?
He was getting it
from Luke, wasn't he?
네이트의 중독으로 루크를 원망한거야?
Did you blame Luke
for Nate's overdose?
사건 현장에서 네가 놓고 간
물건을 찾았단다, 멜라니
We have evidence that puts you
at the crime scene, Melanie.
일이 감당할 수 없게 된거니?
Things get out of hand?
넌 감정적이었고
You're emotional.
그 앨 원망하고 있었지
You blame him for Nate.
그러다 머그잔으로
루크를 내리친거야
Hit him in the head
with the coffee mug.
당신들 정말 끔찍해요
You guys are sick.
그거 알아요?
You know that?
난 도서관에 루크가
괜찮나 보러간거에요
I went to the library to
see if Luke was all right.
네이트의 죽음으로 힘들어하고 있어서요
He took Nate's death pretty hard.
그 시계는 네이트거고요
The watch was Nate's.
그 애 할아버지가 주신거였어요
His grandfather gave it to him.
그 시계를 어딜가든 가지고 다녔죠
He carried it with him everywhere.
루크라면 원할거라고 생각했어요
I thought Luke would want it.
아오, 아오, 아오, 아오!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
난 아직 아무 것도 안 했다고
I haven't even
done anything yet.
- 린지!
- 이거 얼마나 지났지?
CAROLINE: Lindsay.
How long has it been?
이거 진짜 구리다
This thing stinks.
루시, 얼마나 지났냐고?
Lucy, how long has it been?
나도 몰라, 대충 5분 정도?
I don't know, like,
five minutes.
분명 잘 나올꺼야
LINDSAY:
That should be good.
- 그렇겠지?
- 나.. 나도 몰라
- Right?
- I-I don't know.
다른 감자는 없던거야?
You didn't have a potato
이런 이상한게 자란거 말고는?
without these things
growing out of it?
라이터 가지고 있는 사람?
Look. Who has the lighter?
라이터는 왜 필요한건데?
What do you need
a lighter for?
바늘을 소독해야 되니까
To sterilize the needle.
이건 좋은 생각이 아냐
This is a bad idea.
진짜 단 한 번도 안 좋았다고
I don't like this one bit.
캐롤라인, 너 뭐하고 있냐?
Caroline, what are you doing?
망보고 있어
I'm looking out.
계속 망보고 있다고
I'm keeping a lookout.
우리 엄마 아빠는 집에 없는걸
My mom and dad
aren't even home.
내가 벌써 말했잖아
I told you that.
좋아, 알겠어
Okay, good.
그럼 알콜 문지를 것 좀 줘
Now give me the rubbing alcohol.
이젠 알콜도 문질러?
Rubbing alcohol, too?
그냥 녹이나 좀 걷어내려고
I just have to get
the rust off of it.
- 녹? 지금 장난해?
- 농담이야
- Rust? What the hell?!
- Shh! I'm kidding.
너도 감염 당하는건 싫잖아
You just don't want it
to get infected.
좋아, 루시
Okay, Lucy.
감자 좀 귀 뒤에다 대줘
Hold the potato
behind her ear.
하나, 둘..
One, two...
(thud)
프레드가 브로드웨이의
비디오 가게에 갔어
ROSS: "Fred goes to the video
store on Broadway."
프레드, 넌 멍청이야
Fred, you are a moron.
온라인이 있잖아, 짜샤
Online video, dude.
25불에 비디오 3개를 샀대
"He buys three videos for $25."
이런, 아주 날 죽이는구만
God, you're killing me.
이건 겨우 15달러
"This was $15 more
비싼거야 구벌스 사는
값에 2배 보다
* 초콜릿이 발린 땅콩 제품
than twice what he paid
for a box of Goobers."
나도 레이스넷 파긴한데,
진짜 뭐하냐
* 초콜릿이 발린 건포도 제품
I would go with Raisinets,
but whatever.
그럼 구벌스의 가격은 얼마냐고?
"How much were the Goobers?"
첫째로, 겨우 땅콩에 초코나
바른게 5달러나 돼?
First of all, five bucks for
chocolate covered peanuts?
둘째로, 요즘 애들은 대화를
AP 미적분으로 하나?
Second, isn't this kid in, like
AP Calculus?
요! 린지한테 연락 있어요?
Yo, you hear
from Lindsay?
아니
No.
이건 다 뭐야?
What's all this?
빌리 월튼의 핸드폰 내역이죠
Uh, Billy Wharton's
phone records.
정확히는 문자 메세지고요
Text messages, actually.
이 녀석과 루크의 연관성을
도대체 모르겠어요
Uh, I didn't find any contact
between him and Luke.
여기 있는거 기본적인
대수학 문제 아니야?
These are all basic
algebra problems.
그래서 다 이런식이야?
So, they're all like this?
x값을 구하고,
y값을 구하고
Solve for x,
solve for y,
두 개의 전철이 그랜드
센트럴을 떠납니다?
two trains leave Grand Central?
네, 모든게 다 무해한 글이에요
Yeah, everything
is fairly innocuous.
섹스팅도 없고, 아무것도요
No sexting, nothing.
꽤나 실망스러운 부분이네요
It's pretty disappointing.
계속 파야할거야, 반장님은
뭔가 있다고 생각하시니까
I would keep digging, because
Mac's not done with this kid.
내기할까? 네가 지금 외과의사의
손을 가지고 있다는 걸
Bet you're not loving the
fact that you're the one
별로 안 좋아하고 있다는 사실에?
with the surgeon's hands
around here, are you?
말 해야 뭐하겠어
Don't get me started.
무슨 일이야?
What's up?
혹시 루크의 가방에
대수학이랑 관련 된 게 나왔어?
Find anything in Luke's backpack
that's related to basic algebra?
그러니까 단어 문제나 뭐 그런 종류로
You know, word problems
or anything like that?
아니, 내 생각에는 없었는데
No, not that I can think of.
루크 공책이 그 쪽에 있으니까
Uh, his notebooks
are right there,
원한다면 네가 한 번 살펴봐
if you want to
take a look.
난 커피 좀 마셔야겠어
I need a coffee, huh?
- 너도 할래?
- 그래, 주면 좋지
- You good?
- Yeah, I'm good.
내가 보고 있을게, 고마워
Don't worry about it.
Thanks.
반장님, 이것 좀
읽어보셔야 할 것 같아요
Hey, Mac,
you've got to read this.
한 번 보세요, 바로 여기요
Check it out, right here.
타임즈에 보내는 공개 서한
Open letter to the Times.
저는 버논 아카데미의 학생입니다
"I am a student
at Vernon Academy.
그리고 전 지금
용기를 내어 공개하려 합니다
"I feel compelled to bring
to light an epidemic
그것은 어떠한 유행병이
제가 유치원때 부터 다닌
"that is plaguing the school
that I have attended
이 학교에 돌고 있다는 사실입니다
since I was in
kindergarten.
그것은 덱스트로암페타민
남용에 관한 것입니다
"It involves the abuse
of dextroamphetamines.
전 이로인해 가장
친한 친구를 잃었습니다
"I lost a close friend
as a result of this,
그리고 이에 대한 책임자는..
and it is incumbent upon..."
여기서 끊겼군
It cuts off there.
루크는 약을 판게 아니었어요
So Luke wasn't selling
the drugs.
루크는 이 상황을 밀고하려 한 거였군
He was going
to blow the whistle.
긴장 돼 보이네요
He looks nervous.
그럴거네
He should be.
루크가 암페타민 남용에
대해 밝히려고 했으니까
Luke was going public
with the dextro abuse.
복도에서의 싸움도 결국은
그것 때문이었을거에요, 그렇죠?
That's what the fight in the
hallway was about, wasn't it?
루크가 컨닝을 했다는 것도
다 지어낸 말이고요
He made the story up about
Luke cheating off of him.
루크는 빌리를 직면하고
Luke confronts him,
판매를 그만 둘 마지막
기회를 줬는지도 모르지
maybe gives him one last
out to quit dealing.
빌리는 루크에게 꺼지라고 했고요
Billy tells him to piss off.
저건 평범한 점심식사는 아닐거네
This isn't just
some casual lunch.
빌리가 저 아이들에게
엠페타민을 제공하고
If Billy supplied these
kids with dextro,
루크는 그 이름을 대중에
공개하려고 한 거라면
and Luke was going to go
public with the names,
저 애들은 많은 것을 잃었을거에요
they all had a
lot to lose.
저 애들 이름은
확실히 알아놔야겠어요
I'll make sure I
get their names.
저거 프랭크 아니에요?
FLACK:
Is that Frank?
프랭크 맞는데요?
That's Frank.
대체 여기서 뭐하고 있는건가, 프랭크
What the hell
are you doing, Frank?
이거 좋지 않은데요
This isn't good.
내가 가겠네
I'm going.
여기서 뭐하는 건지 말 좀 해주겠어?
You want to tell me
what you're doing here?
저 개자식이 내 아들을 죽였어
That son of a bitch
killed my son.
그건 아직 모르는거야
We don't know that.
내 말 알겠어?
You hear me?
그건 모르는거라고
We don't know that.
- 주머니에 뭐 있는거야?
- 아무것도
- What's in your pocket?
- Nothing.
당장 주머니에서 손 빼게
Take your hand out
of your pocket.
잘 듣게, 우리는 빌리가 판매를
했다는 증거도 가지고 있지 않아
Listen to me, we don't even have
proof that Billy was dealing.
아니, 가지고 있어
Yes, we do.
내가 빌리의 정신과
기록에 소환장을 발부했네
I subpoenaed Billy's
psychiatric records.
자네는 그럴만한 근거도
가지고 있지 않잖나?
You don't have probable
cause to do that, Frank.
스펜서 판사가 나한테 진 빚이 있었지
Judge Spencer
owed me a favor.
빌리는 4번이나 다른 정신과에 갔어
Billy goes to four
different psychiatrists.
저 녀석은 ADHD 증상을 꾸며냈고
He fakes the
symptoms for ADHD,
그 후에 덱스트로암페타민의
처방전을 그들
then he gets a prescription
for dextroamphetamines
모두에게서 받은거야
from all of them.
그게 녀석이 물건을 얻은 경로지
That's where he gets
the stuff from.
- 그 중 두 사람은 심지어 그를..
- 듣고 싶지 않네
- Two of them he doesn't even...
- I don't want to hear this.
스펜서 판사가 자네한테 빚을 졌다고?
Judge Spencer owed
you a favor?
자네 지금 뭐하는건가?
정신 좀 차리란 말이네
What are you doing, Frank?
Listen to yourself.
저 녀석이 루크를 죽였어
He killed Luke.
자네는 수사를 위협할 뿐만 아니라
You're not only jeopardizing
the investigation,
자네의 일도 위험하게 하고 있어
you're risking your job.
우리 일은 우리가 하게 두게
Now let us do what we do.
만약 빌리가 한 일이라면,
우리가 잡을거야
If Billy did this,
we'll catch him.
옳은 방법으로, 호의없이
The right way...
no favors.
내가 자네 상사한테 가게 하지 말게
Don't make me go
to your bosses.
당장, 집으로 가
Now, go home.
내가 나중에 전화하겠네
I'll call you later.
(birds twittering)
준비됐어? 당신이 마지막으로 했던
애정행각을 재연하라!
Okay, ready? Pretend to make
out with your latest crush.
(girls laughing)
(kissing sounds)
오, 딜런!
Oh, Dillon.
딜런?
ALL:
Dillon?
이우!
Ew!
- 진짜 딜런?
- 그래
- Wait, Dillon?
- Yeah.
딜런이 뭐 어때서? 귀엽기만한데
What's wrong with Dillon?
He's cute.
걔 이빨 이상하잖아, 다 었다고
He's got weird teeth...
they're all crooked.
그래서?
So?
게다가 검은색 옷만 입잖아
And he wears all black.
아무래도 걔 고스인가
뭐 그런 것 같아
I think he's goth
or something.
우-, 너 나쁜 남자
좋아하는구나, 그렇지?
Ooh, you like bad boys,
don't you?
아마도?
Maybe.
카우보이는 지루하지
Cowboys are boring.
- 네 차례야
- RED
You're up.
Red.
R-E-D
R-E-D.
Green
Green.
G-R-E-E-N
G-R-E-E-N.
Four.
진실, 당신이 가진 마지막 꿈은?
Truth. What was the
last dream you had?
지금 장난하냐?
Are you serious?
너무 구식이잖아
That's so lame.
아니, 난 듣고 싶어
No, I want to hear this.
좋아
Okay.
다 말해보라고
You were all in it.
난 우리 모두가 상급생이 되고
I dreamed
that we were all seniors
또 모두 운전면허증을 갖는 꿈을 꿨어
and we all had
our driver's licenses.
린지, 너는 컨버터블 트랜스 앰을 타
*GM에서 생산 된 머슬카
Linds, you had
a convertible Trans Am.
트랜스 앰?
A Trans Am?
난 포드 F250 할래
Ford F250, please.
그리고 우리 모두 저수지에
있는 비밀장소로 차를 몰고 가지
And we all drove down to
the reservoir to our spot.
우리는 모두 합격편지를 받는데
We all had our
acceptance letters,
알겠지만, 대학교에서
you know, for colleges.
그래서 편지 봉투를 여는데..
And we opened them up...
모두가 다 다른 학교에 붙어
and we all got into
different schools.
오, 캐롤라인!
Oh, Caroline.
그게 뭐야, 캐롤라인!
What the hell, Caroline?
네 마지막 꿈 말이야,
네 마지막 악몽 말고
Your last dream, she said,
not your last nightmare.
우리 모두 한 학교에
원서를 넣으면 되는거야
KELLY: We're all applying to
one school, and that's it.
그리고 모두가 합격하는거지
And everyone's getting in.
그럼 다 같은 학교에 갈거야
And everyone's going.
- 맞아
- 그거지
- Yeah.
(laughter)
(laughter fading)
NSA로의 전근을 요청하는 바입니다
I'm requesting a
transfer to NSA.
승인하지
Approved.
제가 해낸 것 같아요, 조
I think I did it, Jo.
정확히 뭘 말하는 건데?
What exactly did you do?
- 암호를 풀었다는거죠
- 누구 암호?
- I cracked his code.
- Whose code?
빌리꺼요
Billy's.
빌리의 핸드폰은
His phone was filled
다른 학생들에게 보낸
with these
algebra problems
대수학 문제로 가득했어요
sent to him by
other students.
그런데 문제가 이상할정도로 쉬웠어요
They're way too easy
to be actual questions
이 정도로 똑똑한 애들한테는 말이죠
from students that
are this smart.
으, 나 대수학 정말 싫어했는데
Ugh, I was never
very good at these.
질문은 덱스트로엠페타민에
대한 요청이었어요
The questions are a request
for dextroamphetamines.
그럼 답변은 원하는 숫자가 되는거야?
And the answer is
how many they want?
으흠
Mm-hmm.
그럼 빌리가 판매처였네
So, Billy is dealing.
네, 모든 디테일은 여기에 있고요
Yeah, and the
details are all here.
이걸 보세요
Check this out.
"잭은 골프 연습장으로 갔다"
"Jack goes to the
driving range."
이건 거래가 골프
연습장에서 있다는 말이죠
Means the deal is going to go
down at the driving range,
- 대부분은 첼시 부두였어요
- 알겠어
- most likely Chelsea Piers.
- Okay.
"그리고 공 312개를 샀다"
"Buys a bucket of 312 balls."
세상에 누가 공을 312개나 사겠어요
I mean nobody buys
a bucket of 312 balls.
그러다가 팔 떨어질거에요
Your arm would
fall off.
그러니 이건 거래시간이
3시 12분이라는 뜻이 되죠
So, the deal is going
to go down at 3:12.
"잭이 78개의 공을
치는데 1시간이 걸리면
If Jack hits 78 balls
in an hour,
그가 312개의 공을 치는데는
모두 몇시간이 걸리는가?"
how many hours will it take
for him to hit all 312?
좋아, 알겠어, 알겠다고
Okay, well, all right.
그러니까 정답은..
So, the answer...
말하지 마
don't tell me.
정답은 312 나누기 78이야
The answer is 312 divided by 78.
- 4
- 바로 그거죠
- Four.
- There you go.
한 마디로 이 사람이
약 4개를 원한다는 거겠네
That means this person
wants four pills.
하지만 이게 누군지는 어떻게 알아?
But how do you know
who the person is?
그게, 이 문자를 보낸 사람은..
Well, this one was sent by...
멜라니 로저스에요
Melanie Rogers.
거짓말을 했더구나, 멜라니
You lied to me, Melanie.
거짓말 하지 않았어요
I didn't lie.
넌 우리가 덱스트로암페타민을
판매한게 루크라고
You let us believe that Luke
was supplying students
믿게 내버려뒀잖니, 사실은 판매처가
with dextroamphetamines
when you knew all along
빌리라는 걸 뻔히 알면서도 말이야
it was Billy who was selling.
빌리 뿐만이 아니에요
It's not just Billy.
당장 약 파는 애들
20명도 더 말할 수 있다고요
I can name 20 people,
right now, that sell the stuff.
그건 정말 얻기 쉬워요
It's so easy to get.
대부분은 합벅적인 처방전이에요
Most of them have
legitimate prescriptions
아니면 정신과에 가서
창문을 응시하고는
or they just go into a shrink,
stare out the window,
수업시간에 집중하는 게
얼마나 어려운지를 말하면 되죠
and say they're having a hard
time focusing in school.
넌 그 약을 왜 먹었니?
Why are you taking it?
똑똑한 아이면서
Such a smart girl.
효과가 있으니까요
Because it works.
B+는 충분한 점수가 아니에요
B-pluses don't cut it anymore.
최상위 학교에 가려는 사람에게는요
Not when you're trying
to get into the top schools.
암페타민은 집중력을 높여주고
오래 공부하게 하죠
Dextro makes you focus,
study longer.
효과가 있었어요
It works.
네이트에게처럼 말이니?
Like it worked for Nate?
만약 잡혔다면, 네 모든 미래는
위태로워졌을거란다
If you got caught, you were
jeopardizing your whole future.
네가 한 모든 노력들이 말이야
Everything you'd worked
so hard for.
루크가 대중에 공개하려 한
사실로 큰 피해를 봤겠지
You had a lot to lose if Luke
went public and named names.
전 루크를 죽이지 않았어요
I didn't kill Luke.
그럼 누가 그랬니?
Then who did?
제가 아는 건, 빌리가 알아서
처리하겠다고 한 거에요
All I know is Billy said
he would take care of it.
녀석이 안 보여, 애덤
FLACK:
I'm not seeing him, Adam.
여기 말고 다른데를 찾아야겠어
You've got to help me out here, man.
분명 빌리가 바로 위에 있는걸요
ROSS (on phone): You should be
right on top of him.
아무래도 그게 문제같네
Well, maybe that's the problem.
내가 위에 있고, 녀석이
거리에 있는 것 같거든
I'm right on top of him,
he's on street level.
그럼 저도 못 도와드리겠네요
That I can't help you with.
- 왜냐하면 신호를 보면..
- 워, 워, 워, 워!
- But the signal indicates...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
녀석을 찾았어
I got him.
요!
Yo!
조심해요
Heads up.
이봐!
Hey!
멈춰! 경찰이다!
Stop! Police!
조심해요!
FLACK:
Heads up!
조심해요! 비켜요!
Heads up! Look out!
(grunting)
됐어, 끝났다고
That's it.
It's over.
끝났어
That's it!
저거
LUCY:
That one.
바로 저기 가고 싶어
I'd go to that one.
저 위에 정말 밝은 것 말야
The really bright
one straight ahead.
저건 북극성이야
That's the North Star.
북극칠성이 가르키고
있으니까 알 수 있지
You know because the
Big Dipper points to it.
보이지?
See?
여기를 떠날 수 있을거라 생각해?
Do you think you'll
ever leave here?
몬타나?
Montana?
그리고 어디가는데?
And go where?
글쎄, 나도 모르겠어
Yeah, I don't know.
어디라도
Anywhere.
아니
No.
난 여기가 좋아
I like it here.
난 갈거야
I will.
언젠가는
One day.
바깥은 정말 대단할거야
I like how big
it is out there.
갈 생각이니?
You heading over?
네
Yeah.
아빠가 어디 있는지는
항상 알고있지?
Well, you know where I stand
on this, but...
넌 내 딸이고,
난 널 사랑한단다
you're my daughter,
and I love you.
같이 가기를 원한다면..
If you want me
to go with you...
내가 같이 가주마
I'll go with you.
저도 사랑해요, 아빠
I love you, too, Dad.
하지만 이건 혼자 해낼게요
I gotta do this on my own.
그래서 무슨 일이 있었던거니,
닥터 렌웨이랑
(FLACK) So how are things
going on with Dr. Renway.
아니면 닥터 오버브룩
Or Dr. Overbrook.
아니면.. 닥터 팍스턴
Or... Dr. Parkston.
아니면 닥터 글리슨이랑
Or Dr. Gleeson.
덱스트로암페타민을 파는건
중죄란다, 빌리
Selling dextroamphetamines
is a felony, Billy,
물론 넌 내가 알지 못하는 것까지도
생각할 수 있을거야
and you're looking at I don't
even know how many counts.
하지만 내 생각에
하버드에서는 네 사업 능력을
But I'm guessing Harvard
will not be impressed
그렇게 인상깊어하지는 않을거야
with your
entrepreneurial skills.
네이트 폴슨에게 약을
판매했지, 그렇지 않나?
You sold to Nate Paulson,
didn't you?
그가 얼마나 원한지는 관심 없었고
Didn't matter how
much he wanted,
그가 얼마나 중독된지도 관심 없었겠지
or how out of control
his addiction was,
그냥 그렇게 계속 팔았던거야
you just kept
selling to him.
그래서 루크가 널 비난한거고
And Luke blamed you
for his death,
그러다가 싸움이 일어나게 된거지
that's what the fight
was about, wasn't it?
루크는 밀고한다고 네게 말했을테니까
He told you he was going
to blow the whistle.
그래서 싹을 자를 필요가 있었을거야
But you nipped that
in the bud, huh?
도서실에서 그 앨 찾은거지
You found him in the library.
어디보자, 변호사가 필요하니?
Let me guess: you want a lawyer.
아니요
No.
형량거래를 원해요
I want to trade.
거래? 뭐에 대한?
Trade?
Trade what?
코너스 선생님이요
Mr. Connors.
이걸로 뭘 한거니?
What are you doing with these?
우린 공부 보조품으로 사용했어요
We use them as study aids.
그러니까 집중하고 늦게 자는거요
I mean, to focus,
to stay up late.
취하거나 그런건 아니었어요
Not to get high
or anything.
우리?
We?
학교의 절반이 이 약을 먹어요
Half the school uses them.
선생님네 토론 챔피언 애들이나
Your, your champion
debate guys.
아끼시는 상위권 애들도 마찬가지에요
The prized pupils at
the front of the class.
B+ 애들이 다 A가 된게
이상하지 않으셨어요?
Ever wonder how all
those B-pluses turn to A's?
그래서, 어쩌실거에요?
So, now what?
됐다, 그냥 나가거라
Nothing. Get out of here.
♪
이걸 살인 흉기에서 찾아낸 건가?
You were able to pull those
off the murder weapon?
네, 적외선 이미지로요
Yeah. Infrared images.
파우더를 사용하기에는
There were too many cracks
금이 너무 많이 가 있었거든요
to see a usable
print with powder.
하지만 보시다시피
적외선을 사용해도
But as you can see,
even with infrared,
이미지가 너무 분리되서
제대로 된 완성본이 안 나오네요
there's too much separation and
breaks within key points.
법원에서도 체택이 안 될거에요
It would never hold up in court.
포토샵을 이용하면 어떻겠나?
How are you with Photoshop?
누락된 부분을 재건해서
나한테 프린트 해오게
Build the missing ridges
and print it out for me.
아마 법정까지 안 가도 될 지 모르니까
Maybe we won't need it
to hold up in court.
(buzzer sounds)
(door clanging shut)
혼자 살아남은 아가씨군
The one who got away.
꽤나 긴장한 티가 역력하네
A lot of nerve
showing up here.
아무래도 나한테 할 말이
있는 것 같은데
I'm guessing you've got
something to say,
앉아서 이야기 하는게 어떻겠어?
so why don't you
have a seat, huh?
그 날 금전 등록기에서 얼마를 가져갔어?
How much money did you get out
of the cash register that day?
얼마였어?
How much?
그게 댁한테 얼마나 가치
있었는지를 꼭 듣고 싶다고
I want to know how much those
lives were worth to you.
조금은 실망스러운 토론이 될 것 같군
This is going to be a
disappointing little discussion.
우리 둘 다한테
For both of us.
넌 재판장에 있었지
You were at the trial.
그 때도 들었고, 지금도 들을꺼야
You heard me then, hear me now.
그건 내가 아니었어
It wasn't me.
네가 엄한 사람을 잡은거라고
You ID'd the wrong guy.
맞아
Right.
그래 당신 항소를 읽었어
Yeah, I read your appeals.
그건 모두 신빙성에 관련된 거였지
They're all based
on the unreliability
단일 증인의 증언말이야
of a single eyewitness.
16년 전의 일이었지
16 years go by,
그런데 그 법정에서 아무렇지 않게
날 손가락을 지목 해?
you waltz into that courtroom
and point your finger at me?
제발
Please.
당신한테는 유감을 느껴
I feel sorry for you.
정말로
I do.
대체 여기는 왜 온거야?
Why did you come here?
도대체 뭘 원하는 거냐고?
What is it that you want, huh?
면죄?
Absolution?
네가 느끼는 양심의 가책을 더는거?
You want this off
your conscience?
그럼 여기엔 잘 못 온거라고, 아가씨
You came to the wrong place,
little girl.
그 모든 시간
All these years.
그 모든 항소와
All the appeals.
그 모든 부인들
All the denials.
우리가 이걸 이야기하는 것?
What if we argue this?
아니면 그걸 이야기하는 것?
What if we argue that?
넌 여전히 작은 진실
하나도 못 말하고 있어
You still can't state
the simple truth.
꽤 멋진 시간을
보내셨군요, 코너스씨
You've had quite a
year, Mr. Connors.
2011년 올해의 교사상
2011 Teacher of the Year.
뉴욕 대학에서
고등학교 교사에게 수여하는
And awards for excellence
from New York universities
올해의 우수 교사상까지
honoring high school teachers.
수상금이 5,000달러죠
One for $5,000.
챔피언 토론 팀의 코치기도 하고요
Coach of the debate team
champions.
임금 인상을 받기에
충분해 보이는데요?
Some would think
you deserve a raise.
실제로도 그랬다고 하죠?
The administration did.
많은 운이 있었다고 생각합니다
I've been very fortunate, yes.
물론 많은 노력을 하기도 했고요
But it also was
a lot of hard work.
그랬을거라 생각합니다
I'm sure it was.
당신이 아주 끝장나는 교사라는걸
의심조차 할 수 없죠
I don't doubt that you're
a damn fine teacher.
하지만 당신에게는 좋은 성적과
아이비리그생을
But you have a responsibility
that transcends good grades
찍어내는 것 이상의 책임감이 필요하죠
and churning out
Ivy League students.
그건 이 복도를 걸어다니는
학생들의 안전을
You have a responsibility
to safeguard the welfare
보호하는 일일겁니다
of the kids
who walk these halls.
무슨 말씀을 하시고 싶은지
이해가 안 되는군요
I'm not sure I understand
what you're getting at.
오, 되실텐데요?
Oh, I think you do.
저희가 빌리하고
이야기를 좀 나눴거든요
We had a chat
with Billy Wharton.
루크!
CONNORS:
Luke!
루크!
Luke.
대체 왜 이러는 거니, 얘야?
What has gotten into you, son?
지금 이게 대체 다 무슨 일인거야?
What the hell was
that all about?
- 쟤가 알아요
- 뭘 말이야?
- He knows.
- Knows what?
제가 물건을 파는걸요
That I sell my stuff.
제가 너무 멀리왔대요
He says it's gone too far.
언론에 알리겠다는데,
타임지나 뭐 그런대요
He's going to go public, to the
Times or something.
- 정확히 뭐라고 이야기한거니?
- 저도 몰라요
- What exactly did he say?
- I don't know.
하지만 해결하시는게 좋을거에요
But you better fix it.
제가 추락하면, 선생님도
같이 추락하게 될 거에요
Because if I go down,
you're going down with me.
그 이야기가 미디어로 퍼지는 걸
감당하실 수 없으셨겠죠
You couldn't afford to let Luke
go to the media with his story.
전 루크를 건드리지도 않았습니다
I didn't touch Luke.
그렇죠, 그저 이걸로 하신거겠죠
No. But you did touch this.
전 그저 루크가 이 일로 인해서
I just wanted him
to consider how many lives
얼마나 많은 사람이 영향을
받을지 알았으면 했습니다
would be affected
if he went forward with this.
지금 뭐하는건지를 생각해보렴, 얘야
CONNORS: Luke, consider what
you're doing, son.
저한테 얘야라고 하지 마세요
Don't call me "son."
빌리가 선생님에 대해 말해줬어요
Billy told me that you know.
그건 훨씬 더 복잡한 내용이란다
It's more complicated than that.
아니요, 아니요! 그렇지 않아요
No. No, it isn't.
오래전에 선생님이
하셨어야 했던 일이에요
You should have said
something a long time ago.
그래서 이제 제가 하려는 거에요
And I should have
said something.
난 해고 될거란다
They'll fire me.
직업을 잃게 될거야
I'll lose my job.
내겐 가족이 있단다
I have a family.
딸 말이다
A daughter.
그 전에 생각을 하셨어야죠
You should have thought
about that before.
이렇게 빈다, 얘야
I'm begging you, son.
제발 이러지 마렴
Don't do this.
난 이 학교에 12년을 있었단다
I've been at this school
for 12 years.
네가 유치원때부터 널 알고 있었고
I've known you since
you were in kindergarten.
다른 학생들도 생각하렴
Think of the other students.
그 애들의 미래가 걸린 일이야
The futures that are at stake.
그럼 네이트는요?
What about Nate?
네이트의 미래는요?
What about his future?
전 평생을 아무것도 말하지 않았다는
I have to live
the rest of my life
죄책감을 가지고는 살 수 없어요
with the guilt of...
of not saying anything.
선생님도 마찬가지고요
And so should you.
다른 학생들 미래를
신경쓰는 척 하지마시죠
Don't pretend you're concerned
about your students.
당신은 그저 당신의 미래만을
신경 쓰고 있었던 거잖습니까
The only future you were
concerned about was your own.
(handcuffs clicking)
미안하네
I'm sorry.
♪
(door closes)
다니엘 케이텀,
마지막으로 할 말이 있습니까?
WARDEN: Daniel Katums, do you
have any last words?
제가 했던 행동들에 대해 사과드립니다
I'm sorry
for what I've done.
(girls screaming, gunshots)
(laughter)
(car door closes)
(engine starting)
sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com